Spoiler alert, Focus Fred hit number one
on the app store. I had about like
200,000 downloads to 2 million. I've
learned that the smartness and the
reason why someone is successful in an
indie journey is not whether they're a
good engineer or not. I think the reason
that someone will be successful is their
instinct for product and their instinct
for marketing. Trying to get an engineer
to figure out marketing, they're like,
"No, I don't have to." I'm like, "No,
you do."
>> Welcome to Launched. I'm Charlie Chapman
and today I'm excited to bring you the
co-creator behind the delightful focus
timer app, Focus Friend, Bria Sullivan.
>> Bria, welcome to the show.
>> Hi. So excited to be here. So before we
get into sort of your backstory, I
always like to give you a chance to do a
really quick elevator pitch for the app.
We'll we'll focus mostly on Focus Friend
just so that people know where we're
headed. What is Focus Friend?
>> So Focus Friend is a focus timer that uh
you can set a specific time and then you
have a little bean character that
focuses with you. And if you finish that
timer that you set, then you get an
award and you can like decorate a house
for your little bean character. And it's
an app I created with a YouTuber named
Hank Green.
>> But first, I want to give everyone an
introduction into who you are. So, the
three questions I always ask to kind of
kick off this conversation is where are
you from? Do you have a formal education
related to what you're doing? and then
we can talk about, you know, what your
career was like leading up to sort of
your indie development.
>> I am from about an hour outside of LA
and like Los Angeles, California. I have
lived in a lot of places and now I'm
back to where I'm from cuz I have a
family now and I need lots of family
help.
>> Yes.
>> And Yes.
>> makes a big difference.
>> Yeah. Yes, it does. and I do have a
formal education in computer science
specifically, but I've been making apps
since 2010. I taught myself my my
freshman year of college. I like chose
computer engineering as a as a degree,
but I didn't really know what it was. I
was just like, let me just choose
something. And I didn't know that it
made that programming is how you make
apps. And the iPhone, I think there they
were on the 3GS at the time. And there
was like a ton of different Android apps
being or Android phones being launched.
And I taught myself phone development
specifically.
>> And that was
native like you were building with what
Objective C or Java like what was kind
of the platform of choice at that time?
>> Android first because that was the phone
that I could afford at that time. And
then as I really started to get into app
development, that's when I got a Mac and
then got an iPhone and taught myself iOS
development.
>> And did you jump right into, you know,
building apps and releasing them on the
store and kind of starting a business
right away?
>> I was 18 when the first app came out.
>> Wow. So, how did that go? Were you just
instantly rolling in in cash and you
live in a mansion in LA somewhere in the
hills? I wish that was definitely the
pipe dream that I had because there were
a lot of people at my school that were
doing that or that had known people that
were doing that. There were a lot of
people making apps and living off them
and that was something that I like
really wanted to do. But my first app
was like literally just a like a
calculator type of thing. And then the
second one was a little bit more
successful and it like again I was an
18-year-old girl and if anyone knows
anything about 18-year-old girls, this
is probably true now. We were really
really into zodiac signs at that time. I
made a zodiac compatibility app for like
dating and it was just like a a little
app and it did well but I had no idea
how to monetize it. So again, I was not
making any money, but like downloads
were good.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
Was it I guess it was free then. It
wasn't like paid up front or anything
cuz those were kind of the only options.
>> Correct. Yeah, it was free.
>> Did you keep pursuing this as a an indie
thing or did you kind of go into the
typical career path and get kind of an
engineering job or something like that?
>> I was indie and I had that like full
intention of being indie like when I
graduated. I almost even dropped out of
school cuz I went to school in
California and I had was like super into
like the like let's see I was it was
2010 to 2014 so just startups were so
fun at that time.
>> You wanted to start a company out of
your garage. Typical California.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And like I went to school
about like a 3-hour drive from San
Francisco. I had driven up to San
Francisco a few times and I had wanted
to do that, but I had like a family
event happen where it just kind of like
my entire career trajectory changed. I
had done the like internships at
Microsoft and I was planning on starting
a startup once I graduated, but just
family stuff happened that I was like, I
can't emotionally handle starting a
company anymore. And so I got a job at
Microsoft and that was just I had an
offer and I was like this is all I can
handle. I can't interview anymore. The
indie has been the intention ever since
I learned how to code. So it's been a
long time to coming for it to reach
here.
>> Okay. So you went kind of traditional
career route. Did you keep building apps
on the side? Were you kind of just
always tinkering?
>> I kept going with the Zodiac stuff cuz
there were there there was another app
called like Co-Star that had come out. a
lot of different zodiac compatibility
apps. So, I still kept doing that. I
made a wedding registry one for a bit,
but I was doing it by myself and I I had
been burned by someone I had worked with
before, so I was like just doing it on
my own. And then so from Microsoft, I
went to Google as an engineer and then I
learned that you can't make apps like
you can't make apps at Google
specifically without them owning.
>> Same with Apple, right? Yes, they own
the store and it's a conflict of
interest, I guess.
>> So, I had at least written down when you
start you had to write down like
anything that you had already started
working on
>> prior inventions.
>> So, I I wrote down all the things I had
just a little prototype of and luckily
like yeah, I feel like I was covered at
least. So, I'm like, okay, at least if I
want to work on any of these things,
like I should be fine.
>> That's cool. So, then how did you get
back into into the game? In 2019, like
around 2019, I'd been doing some help. I
was doing another entrepreneurship
thing, helping people without formal
educations get jobs at places like
Google, Microsoft, LinkedIn or just jobs
in general. It was like a passion of
mine. I was also consulting for people
people's startups and helping them like
hire engineers and things like that.
Just it was really fun. It was really
fun working with startups. I'm really
curious because that's a thing that I I
get a lot of questions about and I don't
know as well what is in a quick quick
way. What do you recommend for people
who are wanting to get into into into
tech that don't have, you know, a formal
education background?
>> I'm not going to lie, it was really
hard. That's kind of part of the answer
of like why I stopped. It was so
emotionally draining for me to be like
working with people every day and
working super hard to try and help them
get there and just like it was just a
lot of emotional weight for like them to
keep getting rejections and I'm like I
have a lot of empathy and to the point
where like their rejections felt like my
own rejections and it was just it was a
lot and so that's part of why I went
back to India. I'm like I think that
India might be a better route for people
without formal educations. I had the
itch like I was at Google and I was
working with startups and I'm like I
want to get back into feeling how good
it felt to be indie again and make a
product. And then for all of these
people, I felt like I was kind of also
selling them a pipe dream too, like of
being at a place like I was working at.
And I'm like, let me I'm going to leave
and I'm going to see if I can create a
like match my tech salary with an indie
app.
>> I am curious what you think, you know,
now that it's been a number of years. Do
you think that the indie route is like a
maybe more viable path for somebody
trying to learn? Cuz the reason I asked
that question at the beginning, do you
have a formal education related to what
you do? is in part because it's maybe
50% of people I talk to on here that
have had successful indie apps don't
have an education at least related to to
tech. So to me I feel like the answer
might be yes, but you obviously work
with more of those people. So I'm
curious what you think.
>> I think it's like a yes with a caveat. I
have learned that the the smartness and
the the reason why someone is successful
in an indie journey is not whether
they're a good engineer or not.
>> That is very true. Yes, that's a good
point. Yeah. Yeah. I think the reason
that someone will be successful is their
instinct for product and their instinct
for marketing and their ability to like
do that hard thing that they really
don't want to do. I have found that
marketing is something like trying to
get an engineer to figure out marketing
like they're like no I don't have to.
I'm like no you do. And maybe that's
actually why
such a high percentage of people I talk
to here aren't don't have that formal
education because I think there is this
sort of you know alchemy of different
backgrounds that are required for this
to work as well as a very very heavy
dose of luck that is definitely a major
factor.
>> I think luck matters for some things. I
think someone could get to a 50 to 120K
in yearly like income. I could think
that they can do that without that much
luck personally.
>> Yeah, I guess that's true. I think in a
lot of the stories luck is a big factor,
but that doesn't mean that there isn't a
sort of framework that you can follow.
>> Yeah, there's a there's a little bit of
a formula.
>> Yeah, that's a good point. That's a good
point. Okay. So, I I appreciate the
diversion cuz that that is a topic that
I find very interesting. But getting
back to it, so you you decided you
wanted to get back in the game, the
indie game, and so you did. So, you left
you left the the corporate job or did
you do a kind of feathering out where
you worked on side stuff? I guess you
couldn't if you were at Google.
>> I left um but it was all of the things
in the universe kind of happened at the
right time for me to leave. I was
already planning on leaving and then a
pandemic happened. that helped. I was
already planning on like really
downscaling my life. Like I had built up
this savings. I moved in with my
grandparents. Like a lot changed. But
the universe and like the whole year
matched up with what I needed anyway cuz
I'm like, well, there's nothing to spend
money on anyway because I'm just staying
at my grandma's house. Yeah. So, I left
in 2020 and I had not done game
development before. So, I wanted to get
into iOS again and apps again, but I
just didn't have an idea. And the only
idea I had was in games. So, I'm like,
let's just let's learn how to make
games, I guess.
>> So, that was your your first step into
this was let's build a game. You use
Unity, is that correct?
>> Yes. Well, actually, at first I built
the app, you had built an app in
Flutter.
>> Oh, in Flutter. Okay.
>> Yeah. So, I built it in Flutter and
there wasn't a game engine for Flutter
at that time. I wrote my own game
engine.
>> Oh goodness. Okay.
>> Yeah. Don't do that.
>> And what was the game
>> that game is? It was an idle clicker. It
was like a little idle clicker game. If
you're familiar with like cookie
>> sort of paper clip like you keep like
hitting buttons and then you kind of
gain the ability to make more faster and
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> That was really popular for a while.
>> Yeah. So I did that but I did a spin. I
wanted to make a game about boba like
bubble tea. And um
>> this is a throughine through your
career. I feel like we'll get more into
boba.
>> Yeah. So, I knew I wanted the that boba
specifically to be the thing that makes
people that would be the subject of what
I'm making. And then in the pandemic,
the only lines I saw outside even in
like April of 2020 were at boba shops.
Like not at Yeah. Not anywhere else
except for like boba shops. So, I'm
like, "Okay, maybe this is a good
decision."
>> So, the game was what? You're running a
a bobati like shop basically.
>> Yeah. And during that time I was also
learning marketing cuz that had been
like my weak spot at that time. I did a
Udemy course and I I think Udemy is
where you know there's like Udacity.
There's so many. But I remember it at
least taught me the basics of marketing
and then that's when I started like
doing my own marketing on TikTok. And
that's where I think as a marketing
person and a product person, I feel like
that's where things really really
started to um to change for me.
>> So you took a it was just one of those
Udemy courses or something like that on
it was on like UGC marketing or like
what what specifically was it about?
>> No, it was a general marketing course
just learning like the basics of
marketing like what how to craft a
marketing message. So at that time it
was still talking about like different
platforms that didn't exist anymore but
the concepts were still things that I
could take away from. So I only finished
I want to say the first like 20% of it
but I felt like I got what I needed from
it.
>> But you felt like it was a valuable sort
of platform to build on.
>> So that's what helped me get to I'm like
okay where do my customers like I I know
I want to reach people who are around
this age group like this type of
archetype. I had a couple cousins in
that age range. I called them and asked
them, "Hey, what what platforms do you
use the most?" And they all said Tik Tok
at that time. And so I started that's
when I learned how to become a Tik Tok
creator.
>> So you had a game by that point you had
gotten to the point where either was it
released already by then or Okay. So you
were working on a game and you started
kind of crafting a message or at least
in your head crafting a message. Did you
start pre-arketing before you released
it or kind of what's the order of
operations there? Yes, I started
pre-arketing it, but I already kind of
had an idea of what I was building for
that app. I started marketing it in
around November and then I launched it
in February. So, I was marketing it and
getting pre-orders and all of that up
until February. The app did okay, like
you know, it made an income, like it
made an income and it was okay, but I
realized it wasn't the app that these
people were looking for. And so instead
I started building a product.
>> When you say marketing prearketing was
that these were like Tik Tok videos
showing off the app. Is that what it
was?
>> And then when the app actually came out
it wasn't exactly what people were
looking for. And so like it did all
right but that's when I was like I'm
going to re kind of reverse what I'm
going to do for the next app cuz it was
just the the app wasn't working to where
I'm like this is probably not worth
working on. So, but I still had this
audience that I was building. I was
still posting on Tik Tok. And so, I'm
like, let me reverse it and like now I
know exactly what people are looking
for. Let me make something based on what
they're looking for and um what they
like.
>> That audience was follow like this is
your like a personal account. The
audience was following you as a person.
So when you talked about the journey, it
was the journey of building the app was
part of this, not just like you're
marketing the game as a as if you're a
company or something like that.
>> Yeah. I was doing it like, hey, this is
something that I'm making follow along
type of thing.
>> Okay. You're building an audience, which
actually this is interesting because
we're going to get to, you know,
building an app with an influencer and
how that all plays in. But this is kind
of what you were doing, but building
yourself up as an influencer kind of
from the beginning. Man,
>> it's interesting cuz I find that some
people that do this end up starting to
become an influencer instead of more
focused on like their product and that's
just something that happens. But it is a
good strategy and I wasn't the first one
doing it. There were a lot of other game
developers doing it too at that time.
And Tik Tok 2020 and 2021 Tik Tok was a
very fun and very easy time to get
followers and get clicks and downloads.
So, you said that this first game wasn't
working necessarily, but you had an
audience. Where did you go from there?
>> I started interviewing. Like, I think
that's one of the secret sauces of what
even with Focus Friend Success now is
just really getting to know someone and
the person that you're making this for.
Like, at first I was just I it was my
friends and my family members and even
myself, but it's really getting to know
the person. And so I made another Boba
app, but it was based on kind of what it
was a lot of iterating on what people
liked and what they the look of what
they liked. The look matters so much.
>> And how are you interviewing people? Was
this like calls out on like Tik Tok
followers or is this you had something
in the app for people to reach out or
like how did you find people to
interview?
>> Yeah, Tik Tok followers and I would live
stream on Tik Tok a lot and this is
before I had a kid so this is when I had
time to do stuff like this.
>> Yeah. before I had Yeah. So, I would
just be live streaming for hours and
just like ask people stuff and then I
would just ask a question and people
would just be sitting there and I would
like draw something out and be like, "Is
this what you're talking about?" Okay,
what about this? I would share my screen
and I would ask them, "Is this more of
the vibe that y'all like or is this more
of the vibe that y'all like?" It wasn't
like you were interviewing them about
features or what problems are obviously
not what problems you're trying to solve
because it's a game, but it it was
almost like like a brand marketing
sessions that a big company would do,
but you have the audience right there
and you could like in real time
tweak and feel out and and I imagine
from the influencer side, you're also
like that audience feels like part of
them is in the app now, right?
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. So, this is as you're building
your second app that you're doing a lot
of this. Mhm.
>> And then what was the second app? Was it
also like a click click style game or
was it a different thing altogether?
>> This one was way more interactive. So it
was still a boba like run a boba shop
type game. So it's called Boba story. If
you want to make a game ever, play games
that you like and take things that you
like from those things. So I kind of
based the functionality on that and I
had done kind of like a spin on it and
some other games that I had loved from
like the '9s and early 2000s. And so I
kind of took elements from all those
things, put it into this app, and it's
way more of a create your own bubble tea
drink. And that was something that was
like the thing that people cared about
the most when I would be posting about
Tik Toks. They would be caring about
what ingredient is. They're like, "Let
me have the craziest looking boba
drink." That's all people cared about.
So all they cared about was like, "How
do I make the craziest looking drink?"
>> Okay. So, you honed the game in more
towards that then I imagine.
>> Yes.
>> You said you're running a shop, but like
what's the kind of gameplay mechanic?
>> Just decorating and expanding the shop,
basically unlocking more stuff. There
was an inflection point. So, Tik Tok
only got me to a specific time. Once I
added like the really crazy ingredients
like dog boba like and cat boba like
it's literally like each boba pearl is a
cat or a heart or a star or something.
That's when things really exploded cuz I
put that behind a like you have to
unlock it was like a combination. I
didn't do this intentionally but now I
know and I tell people any other builder
I guess the way I had designed that
screen was very easy to share and that
like super s first it was a secret there
was no hey you can figure out you can
buy hints or whatever you can't you
can't figure this out unless you work
with other people and it exploded on Tik
Tok on YouTube on Instagram and this is
other people shar sharing their screen
recordings of the or or screenshots I
guess of
>> their crazy creations.
>> So Tik Tok itself so that app launched
in October and then from October to
February I'd been posting Tik Toks and
it was doing good. Like I think I had
around like 200,000 downloads by that
point is still amazing.
>> And this just the the monetization for
this is it inapp purchases or is it like
a onetime payment thing? What was the
How was it?
>> Just rewarded rewarded ads. So, no like
banners or anything like that. It's
like, hey, if you watch an ad, then you
get to exchange it for currency. So,
they'd watch like a 30. So, that was it
from then. I had about like 200,000
downloads, but once I added that
feature,
like it exploded. I went from, I think,
200,000 to 2 million in the next. And
because it's ads, that scales pretty
linearly or at least user or active
users scales linear linearly to your
monetization actually.
>> Wow. Okay.
>> I think this is it's a very strong part
of my journey and I don't know if it's a
good thing or not is getting too ethical
about monetization. That's kind of it's
something that I think might hold me
back in some ways, but I specifically
chose a a way that you only have to
watch an ad if you choose to. Like, you
can play the entire game without having
to watch an ad. So, I had people that
were completely unmonetized.
>> And I did that from a moral perspective.
Is that a good thing? I don't know. And
that kind of goes into a focus friend as
well because we chose that route. And we
can talk about that later.
>> Yeah. I feel like there's
for one, the nice thing about being
independent, whether it's just you or
like you're not beholden to shareholders
or whatever, is that you can make these
decisions. Like it's okay to just have a
business that makes less money than it
optimally could, but you feel better
about it, right? I also think there's a
bit where
certain
growth strategies work better by having
that kind of attitude, right? like uh
Fortnite, you know, famously is like
there's no pay to play. Like that was
like that's the best way to really super
monetize something, but it it allowed
the things to grow faster because it was
more appealing to people. I think in
your case, if one of the major growth
levers was this sort of social loop of
like the more people use it, the more
your organic marketing grows and it's
like a flywheel almost, then
having it be something that more people
can use. Even if they're not giving you
any money, they're actually potentially
still contributing to the business
because they're sharing it out. Um,
obviously who knows if that's actually
true or not, but there I think there's a
bit where that's actually potentially
even the better business move. But even
if it's not, I don't think it matters.
It's like if you're able to sustain
yourself and you're comfortable with
that, you don't have to make the most
money possible by extracting everything
you possibly can out of everybody.
>> It's true. However, it's hard to stay
there when there are other apps that
make more than us, for example, or are
able to do those things. And it's hard
to not kind of change move the goalpost
for yourself. Like, I had a goalpost of
what I wanted to be at a year ago and
two years ago, and I hit that, and I'm
past those things, and I'm still not
satisfied. This is kind of a
philosophical thing, but
>> no, I think this is a this is really
funny actually. This is this is kind of
a running theme with this show. When I
started this show in 2020, so like right
in your kind of time frame here, I felt
like a big part of what we talked about
a lot was it's okay to make money.
Because in the indie sphere it was very
like you know doing a subscription or or
utilizing a hard payw wall or having
doing AB testing even was often really
frowned upon as like a everything should
just be about making it the best
experience possible. But then we watched
all these big well-known indie apps fall
down because they couldn't sustain their
companies anymore. And so I felt like
there was this narrative of like it's
okay to make money like there's a
balance that you can have. And then it
feels like in the last few years in
particular, that needle has just swung
way hard to the other side where I feel
like now I'm constantly preaching it's
okay to not make all of the money.
You're allowed to, you know, do this.
But it is hard. I imagine you run in
similar circles as me where you see
these people making enormous amounts of
money doing small differences to what
I'm comfortable doing and I'm like,
well, you know, maybe I should just do
this or just do that. and the tooling
makes it easier and easier to do, right?
And so, yeah, it's it's definitely a
weird balancing act.
>> It's hard when being on social media is
something that is really helpful for
being able to stay in the know on things
and to make sure that your product is
also like up to-date in in like what
people are expecting, but it you can't
drown out the other voices. It's hard
not to see other people reaching things
that I'm like, I think I could do that.
I think I could do that, too. But it
makes it 10 times harder harder when
I've made these very strict moral lines
and they're very strict with focus
friend. And so there's a potential where
we have reached kind of like the peak of
where we're at. Hopefully not, but it's
something that I think about every day
right now. Let's get into focus friend
then. So sure I think that's the next
one on your list after Boba story. So
you have the successful app that's
running is it's Boba Story is still out
today, right?
>> It's still it's still running. I built
that one in Unity. So I did not have to
I did not where you built your own
engine. Yeah, exactly. So then what led
to to focus friend? Like what's what's
the story there?
>> Like I mentioned with Tik Tok and
building my audience and seeing that it
was a way for me to monetize. I was
like, this is also a way to monetize an
audience. Um, so my partner is also a
YouTuber and I love the creator space.
If you've ever met any other YouTubers
or full-time creators, es like he's in
the science space, so they're the best
people. Like they're so awesome. Those
specific creators are like the best
people. I learned a lot about how they
have to monetize and monetizing is very
difficult. like YouTube after Tik Tok,
like it just it's hard for them to kind
of support themselves monetarily now.
It's not the 2016 people are getting
$100,000 deals like they were before.
And monetizing an audience, I learned
with making Boba Story that this is a
way that someone can monetize an
audience. I was like an app. There were
times that I didn't work for 4 months on
end and I still had an income. My income
did not change.
>> It's very much the passive income, you
know, obviously there's a ton of work
leading to that, but it is flexible and
a sort of unique way.
>> Yeah. And so I got really interested in
it being a way for for a YouTuber to
monetize their audience. So, I had been
it was something I I was very passionate
about and I had talked to like my
partner about it and I was thinking
maybe one of his friends would be
interested and I had known my partner
also taught on Hank Green has a channel
called Crash Course. He had taught um
machine learning on one of those
channels many years ago and I was like,
"Oh my gosh, someone like Hank Green
would be the most ideal partner to work
with." But maybe one day I'll be able to
work with him. I was like, "Maybe one of
your other friends."
>> For the moon, right? Shooting for the
moon.
>> Anybody who doesn't know, Hank Green is
>> he's arguably in the the top five at
least of like well-known, you know,
science YouTubers probably, right? Is
that is that accurate? In my world, at
least that seems to be the case. Yeah,
>> I would say so. And a lot of college
students and anyone who had like has
like gone to college in the past 5 to 10
years has probably heard of him or at
least if they went to school for
something science related.
>> Exactly. It's hard to avoid ending up on
one of his explainers just because
they're so good
>> and they have a lot of free education
channels. So he was someone I was like I
really would one day that's like a dream
person to work with. But I thought maybe
one of his other uh one of my partner's
other creator friends would be
interested. Someone with like maybe a
million subscribers. Like I would love
to see if this experiment of monetizing
an audience like if this is something
that can sustain a YouTuber. Yeah. So
that's why I was like interested in it.
And it just so happened that I just
landed from a family vacation in like
Japan and I saw that Hank was about to
be in town and I was like Chappelle, can
you please I was like, I want it. Like,
can you please see if he I was like,
Hank is performing his um his standup
special like 15 minutes from our house.
Like, can you please just see if he'd be
interested in hanging out? I just want
to meet him. Like, I wasn't going to
pitch him. And I didn't pitch him. I
just wanted to meet him cuz I was such a
huge fan of his. Like, him and his
brother were like the reason I even
started being interested in watching
YouTube in general. like for fun I would
watch their education channels and he's
like okay I'll ask and so Hank asks us
to dinner and we're just chatting Hank's
super nice my partner starts bragging
about Boba's story and Hanks and I guess
I had said something in that dinner
about creators having apps or games or
something and that was it and like I had
met a hero and afterward I don't know if
you're an anxious person like me. But I
just afterward I was like, "Oh my god,
this is the worst thing ever. I just met
a hero." I was like, "I just met a hero
and I'm just analyzing every small thing
that I had said to him. Oh my god, was
that stupid?"
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Does he think I would forget
everything about me? I've definitely
been there.
>> I was like, I feel very Yeah, I feel
very observed right now. But anyway, a
week later, he sends me a message on Tik
Tok and he said that he had not been
able to stop thinking about like
something I had said at dinner and he
messaged me on Tik Tok and reached out
and asked for a meeting and out of that
meeting basically came Focus friend. You
can correct me if I'm wrong, but what
I've gathered just from listening to
lots of his content over the years, he's
also pretty both savvy and kind of
enjoys the the sort of business side of
being a influencer and creator. Like he
doesn't shy away from trying different
ideas and things like that. So that also
feels like something that kind of would
fit in. I thought he would be way more
just kind of like wacky science guy, but
he is way more businesssavvy than I had
expected.
>> Yeah, that that tracks. Uh so, okay. So,
you're interested. So, I guess it
literally starts with the premise is,
hey, I can build apps and have all this
experience with monetizing on the app
store. You have a big brand. And also,
you know, did you already have ideas to
pitch or was it like let's just
brainstorm and see what what's something
that his audience would be interested
in?
>> Well, it was a no from his perspective
actually from the beginning. Like yeah,
it was a no, but we were supposed to
actually make something for one of his
other channels, but like the meeting was
ending and I just said as the meeting
was ending, I just said, "What about a
focus timer?" like a crash course focus
timer and that's when he was like, "Oh,
interesting. H let me think about that.
That sounds very interesting." And then
the call ended and then
>> Oh my gosh, that's so cinematic. Like,
>> yeah,
>> you threw your Hail Mary and then the
call ends and you don't know how it's
going to Oh my goodness. Okay.
>> Then he texts me like an hour later
like, "I love this idea. Oh my gosh, I
love it." And then we just kept talking
about what the idea could be. And so I
just like got to work on like coming up
with like a concept. I drew stuff and
yeah and he like pitched it to his team
and they were not interested. He was
still very excited about the idea though
and so that's why it became a Hank Green
app and not um
>> that's what I was that was my next
question is like it's not branded as a
crash course or any of his other sort of
ventures. It is just here's this app you
know an a Hank Green production or by
Hank Green. trying to figure out how
it's in the green.
>> Okay. Yeah. So that's why that's the
case is it literally is
him like it's his own thing with you as
opposed to part of one of his other
ventures.
>> It was going to be part of like one of
his companies, but no, it just became a
no one they didn't really understand why
it would be a good idea. So then we
ended up it was like okay well we're
friends we're friends now so let's just
keep doing it. We're excited about it.
and I just kept working on it and that's
when I started interviewing his audience
instead of crash a crash course
audience.
>> You said you did interviews like what
was the sort of central thesis that was
exciting to both of you and then how was
that shaped to what it became through
all these interviews and and sort of the
development cycle. It was gonna be way
more gamey at first. Like there was
gonna be a lot more like rarity and um
there was a lot more it was way more
game than it was app. And as I started
interviewing people, it became way more
app than game cuz we're in that like
middle space kind of where it's like a
gamified Yeah. Where it's like a
gamified app.
>> And what pushed you in that direction? I
know you said interviews, but was it
people specifically saying they don't
want it to be a game or why did it push
that way? It was the way that people
were interacting with the app. It just
wasn't making a lot of sense. I think
when it comes to someone with ADHD in
particular, I think just making things
very very very simple to understand.
Like we had all these like rarity
matrixes and all of these things. And so
we switched it to being like you just
earn a number a number of currency based
on the number of minutes that you did
and that's it. which makes sense for
something designed to help people focus.
You don't necessarily want to be drawing
them into this massive spreadsheet. You
mentioned ADHD. Was that part of the
initial premise as well is that it was
kind of targeted at that audience.
>> No, it was just for Hank's audience.
Spoiler alert, Focus Fred hit number one
on the app store.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. So, I just did before I So,
because it makes sense for for the story
to make the story make a little bit more
sense, but we had no idea. We were just
trying to do a Hank's core core core
fans will like this app. That was just
that was the only thing we were really
going for.
>> It just so happens that
>> Hank's core core core fans also have
ADHD.
And
>> that you discovered that through the
interviews or Hank just knowing his
audience and that kind of organically
came up.
>> It came up way way later. So, it was
just interviewing his audience and he
didn't even announce like, "Hey, fill
out this survey." He just put it in a
description in one of his Vlog Brothers
videos and it was just a Google form
that says, "Do you use focus timers?" It
just interviewed all of those people and
then just really got to know those
people. I worked very hard on the what
the interview would look like and what
questions I would ask, what I really
needed to know about these people. And
then so there was like one half of the
interview and then the other half was
more about like look feel what the bean
should look like. So pairing those two
things together I got to know the person
and then I was like okay almost all of
these people are gravitate gravitating
towards this color palette. When it
comes to like female audiences too and
anything gified like the look and feel
matters so much for organic reach.
>> I think it matters for productivity apps
too. It's just people don't naturally
pay as much attention. Certainly, I'm
just as guilty of that. And I think
you're right in terms of it's not just
for you using it, but also the how
attractive is it in a ad format, right?
Whenever people are seeing screenshots
or screen captures or whatever.
>> Yeah. It's like what's going to make
someone convert and the way something
looks is a huge reason why people
convert.
>> You said people are gravitating towards
this. Are you showing like multiple
options and saying is it like going to
the dentist or going to the eye doctor
and they're like A or B and you're kind
of just honing in?
>> I showed six different art styles, six
different beans and six different color
palettes, something like that.
>> And then I just said like choose one and
then they all kind
>> you just grew over time working on your
other apps or had you done that
professionally or had education that led
you towards doing this kind of market
research? cuz that feels like, you know,
very like professional market research
that most indies I've talked to have
definitely I've never heard of anybody
doing it to like kind of this level.
>> I think it's something that happened
over Tik Tok like as I was doing it on
live streams.
>> Um like as I was asking people, it just
seemed easier to like I would just show,
okay, which one do you like? Which one
do you like? I'm just going to show them
all six at once.
>> And it organically systemized This is
This is one of those I just love these
kinds of stories. I don't know. There's
a Steve Jobs quote. I can't remember how
I think it's him. Maybe it's him quoting
somebody else, but it's like the whole
when you look at the past, it's easy to
draw a line through everything, but in
the future it's squiggly or whatever,
but it's I love these like you can
follow somebody's story and be like this
weird thing you did here, even if it
didn't seem like it mattered, which it
did, but like you're just slowly
accumulating these skills that become
really important for things you do later
in your life. I just love that kind of
stuff.
>> The compound interest of skills.
>> The compound interest of skills. Yes.
Okay. So, you're building this app over
a pretty long period of time before you
released it, right? I feel like I
remember hearing whispers of it, you
know, like a year before I even heard
about it coming out.
>> Yeah. So February 2024
was when we had started like development
of it and it was supposed to launch in
July of 2024. I got pregnant in July of
2024 and I was having a lot of issues
with my team cuz I had hired some people
and like Yeah, hiring people with an
indie budget was really hard.
>> Yeah, hiring people with a VC budget is
really hard. Uh
>> yeah, I
>> imagine it's much harder with a lower uh
you know
>> Yeah, cuz I was paying for everything
out of my pocket like for up and up
until that point and even like up until
the launch of Focus Friend. So I got
pregnant and I had a condition called HG
where it's like morning sickness all
day. And so I couldn't I couldn't leave
my bed or even look at a screen for
almost like 6 months. So, I would work
as much as I could
during those six months. And then we had
a plan to launch in January of 2025. And
I had actually interviewed with Revenue
Cat in December of 2025 cuz I was like,
"Okay, I'm running out of money and I
don't know if this app is going to work
out." So, I gave birth to my daughter 15
weeks early. My daughter was in the
hospital for almost 4 months. So, my
entire journey got delayed a whole year.
and I did not work when she was in the
hospital and Boba's story is what just
sustained me until that time. She got
out of the hospital. We actually just
had her homecoming anniversary a few
weeks ago. And then I'm like, "All
right, I'm spending 2 weeks and um
figuring out how to be a mom and then
I'm going to start breaking my computer
out during nap time. I have to make
Focus Run work or watch this." Like,
it's gotten delayed so many times. I
don't want to disappoint Hank. I don't
want to like like he's someone I looked
up to and I was just like let's make
this work and I'm just going to keep
working and making and trying to make
good decisions for focus.
>> I mean knowing where this leads this is
like 2025 has to be one of the most
insane years of
>> Yeah.
>> ever for anybody.
>> It was like the lowest Yeah. It was like
the lowest time of my life cuz like if
anyone's ever had a child in the
hospital, it's the worst thing ever. It
is the worst thing ever. and then
hitting number one on the app store like
a few months later like the best thing
ever.
>> Let's get to the launch then. And but
really quickly, we can't we can't not
address the bean of the situation. So,
>> right,
>> the main character of the app is this
little little bean. What's the sort of
backstory? Where did that come from? And
like I guess you already kind of talked
about the how it developed over all
these interviews, but yeah, what's the
story there?
>> Pink just said magic bean and then we
just ran with it. Yeah. Uh, and I guess
he has like a in his Hank Green lore
like of his super hardcore fans called
Nerd Fighters. I guess they there's some
bean stuff. There's some bean jokes
there. Um, he has like a c he has a
little Furby made of beans on his desk.
>> Like that's the extent of it.
>> Yeah, there's no reason other than his
audience. It's an inside joke between
him and his audience. The design of it
is very reminiscent of I wish I could
recall the name off the top of my head,
but the what is the name of that
Japanese style like the egg yolk
character or
>> the Yeah, very cutesy.
>> Very very cutesy and like the little
bubble butt kind of on the back. That's
what makes me think of the egg. Was that
something that right from the beginning
you s sort of gravitated towards based
on your style or was that coming out of
this sort of long interview and and
growth of the design that you went
through?
>> It was the interviews. So I showed like
20 different options of beans and art
styles and everything. Like I had tons
of different art styles to choose from.
Some that I was gravitating towards but
there was a very different direction we
were going in. like very different, very
lowfi. That was what we were originally
going for. There's a show called like
Bee and Puppy Cat. Like we were kind of
going for that and that is not what
people were gravitate gravitating
towards. They were way more towards some
other stuff. So we changed the the art
style based on what people gravitated
towards.
>> It feels like the bean combined with
Hank's kind of star power.
>> The bean is the thing that really seemed
to like catch people's attention and it
it was its own story. That's so cool
that it wasn't just
>> you have no like you literally worked
and sort of grinded towards that which
is really interesting and different than
a lot of the indie stories where like I
was saying a lot of it feels like luck.
I think it's clear that in this case
there was way more strategy going into a
lot of this than I I realized for sure.
So you got went through all of that
insanity of 2025. What was the release
strategy? the point is to monetize
Hank's audience. So, I'm guessing that's
part of it. But, yeah, what were you
thinking going into that? I guess
>> we had one strategy and we changed it.
So, I want to say it because this is
important for other indies. Something I
learned with all of the other like indie
game developers. There was this hack
that we would all do and um just gather
pre-orders for as long as we could, like
90 days I think is the is the max. We
would try to get as many pre-orders as
possible and do a big launch because you
could hit number one or you could re
really high high on
>> the Nikita beer method. I think
>> I don't think that's actually his but I
actually don't know but I feel like
that's what cuz he would he could just
come out with
>> esoteric apps that could hit number one
based on seemingly all these little
hacks. And that that's one that I know a
lot of people try to do.
>> Yeah, that was something that all of us
on Tik Tok creators would do. like it
was because you would spend you would
just post Tik Toks, gather wish lists or
whatever or gather all of the pre-orders
and it helped with visibility and you
didn't really have to have a real app
like it didn't have to work. You're
already getting downloads and then it's
like that's all you really need.
>> And then the story of it being number
one is its own sort of sort of like
propeller for the very beginning.
>> Yeah. But I had a friend who has hit
number one a few times with their apps
and he has said that he has had a bunch
that have like gone from up to number
one and all the way down within a few
months
>> all the way down like to nearly zero. He
said that the one that went up and then
had a long tail and he just sold for
many millions of dollars or many tens of
millions of dollars. Those ones that
were from grinding like nailing what the
experience is like from beginning to
end. And so I took that advice and I
changed our strategy and I was like we
can't hit number one. We were going to
just announce it and collect pre-orders
and all that. And I told Hank like I
don't think that we should do that. and
he's just like, "Okay, cool." So, in
July, we I was like, "Okay, the app's
ready." He posted about it on a
community post on YouTube. I think we
got like 20,000 downloads from in that
week from him, like just posting on a
community post on YouTube. So, so much
bad feedback during that time. People
were so mad at us for um one, we didn't
have a lifetime option. Thought it was
gross that we was just a subscription.
What was the reason for going
subscription? I we didn't talk about
that.
>> We went with subscription for I think
it's just something that worked well for
that. Like they have a Patreon and
subscription boxes and that's just
something that just monetization wise
worked. That was something I also worked
really hard on was the monetization and
figuring out what worked and what felt
not gross cuz the only thing that you
really got with the subscription was
being able to earn socks or earn the
currency at 3x the time. So you could
use it all for free and there was just
kind of a benefit for supporting the app
basically.
>> Yeah. And then there was another and
then um skins like to make the bean look
like other stuff. But also last minute
this is where I'm like is there some
divine intervention happening with AI
prior to where AI was at that time. I
could not figure out. So I wrote this
app in Unity and Unity does not have
access to a lot of stuff that like
native apps do. But there's just a lot
more users who actually use those things
in React Native and stuff. So there's
libraries for things like live
activities, dynamic island, like all of
those things. I couldn't use any of that
and and a screen time API all or it's
called family controls. Like I couldn't
do any of that. Um but with AI, I was
able I was like, "Oh my gosh, I can
figure it out now." like it can get me
to that point of getting to I can write
the native stuff with AI or at least
like help write these bridges from
Unity. So that's what really also helped
is being able I'm like okay all of these
native functions I can put behind the
pro subscriber
payw wall for example
>> and uh you know just out of curiosity uh
for the inapp purchase part of it how
did you handle that? I chose revenue cap
from the beginning. I hope that payw
walls is something that I can use soon
because I'm not sure. I think they added
Unity support recently. I had used the
like purchases API on Unity before, but
it was just going to be really hard to
do subscriptions and there wasn't a lot
of like support for subscriptions on
Unity and I just I didn't really know
what to do and I was like, well, I know
Revenue Cat and it works. So, it was
built in from the beginning and it was
super easy. So you you announced it kind
of sort of quietly on a community forum
and people were very mad. One because of
subscriptions, no lifetime options, and
then you were going to say some others
before I rudely interrupted.
>> Android was missing some things. This
help emails and reviews were really bad.
Like and the comments under his post, I
mean, there were people who loved it,
don't get me wrong. There were people
who really, really loved it, but there
were also like people who were really
mad and I had to respond to feedback. I
don't know if you've talked to other
people who've done this sort of
influencerbased
marketing channels or or monetizing an
influencer brand, but it's like feels
like it's more prone to this type of
thing because people feel such a strong
connection that it's not like they see a
thing and then they're just like
whatever, that's not for me and they
bounce off. But it's like there's this
personal like attack maybe even feeling
where this person's doing something that
I don't like but I like this person and
like those clash and can cause those
feelings. Do you think that that rings
true?
>> Yes. And that was a huge reason we had
we made like various particular
decisions. There are things that that
every app does. They have an advertising
tracking ID for example to do paid
acquisition. If someone wants to have
ads within the app so that there are
people who can't afford things that they
can just pay with like watching ads, you
have to collect some information for
those ad networks. supposed to launch
before panels, but with all of like the
drama of my pregnancy and child, it
delayed us. And I really paid attention
to why people were mad. And I was like,
every app on your phone uses those
things, but for some reason, he's not
allowed to. So, that taught me
>> because it's because it's him and then
you're in I think there's also an
element where it's like, well, he's a
famous rich person. That's the mental
model. And so like why are they doing
that? Whereas if it's a nameless also
unfamous rich person who runs a giant
company or whatever, it doesn't have
that same emotional connection maybe.
But yeah, that is interesting cuz that
was a pretty high-profile example of
somebody sort of experimenting with
monetizing their audience and yeah,
there was quite a bit of backlash from
from I feel like.
>> Yeah. So, I learned because we were
admonetized also in the beginning and I
I had to like call Hank and be like, I
think for your reputation, we should
take this out. Even though we're now
going to have way less people monetized,
I think we should take this out. The
advertising tracking thing, we also
didn't do any tracking. And that's
something that people really cared
about. That also came up in the
interviews for when I was talking to
people and when I was just trying to get
to know them, they
often said how much they cared about
their privacy and I didn't ask, they
just said it and it was something
>> so obviously it's an important thing to
them that they're thinking about when
they think of the apps just generally.
>> Yeah. So, we also made the decision to
not have an advertising tracking ID,
which as you probably know and everyone
knows, that basically kills paid
acquisition for us.
>> Yes. Yes. Exactly. Or at least being
able to do it
>> well. You can do sort of brand marketing
style stuff, but it's it's very
different when you can't basically run
the machine and let it be like this is
exactly how much value you're getting
out of these users and so you can pay
this much and now you have, you know,
the mini money printing machine. Yeah,
it makes my life a little bit harder and
um I have to get a lot more creative,
but I'm like I'm just trying to look at
it as this is the next skill, I guess,
for me to uh for me to learn. But yeah,
so we got so much feedback and we're
getting emails and emails and emails and
this is and I still didn't think it was
going to do that well. I was like, okay,
well, what it did, it's probably going
to do do 10x what we did and that I'm
like, all right, what's going to happen?
public on the store by this point or was
this like a a test flight beta? So, this
is public on the store.
>> Yeah, we we just didn't like tell a lot
of people about it other than that
community post. And so, we got tons of
feedback and I I was just responding to
the emails. And meanwhile, by the way,
this whole time I'm still taking care of
a newborn child.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> It was a it was a very um a very
sleepless time of my life.
>> I imagine so. Um Yeah. So, it was
getting lots lots and lots of emails.
And once the emails started to dwindle a
bit where people weren't complaining,
where I wasn't getting like 10 emails or
no, it was way more than that. I was
getting so many a day. And once those
started to feel like they were waning
and I was addressing all of those things
that people had issues with, I was like,
"All right, Hank. Like, I think I think
we're ready. I think we're ready to
actually do the full launch." And that's
when the real genius of Hank Green
really kicked in. Oh my god.
>> So, how'd that go? Cuz it was it felt
like it just took over the internet for
a while.
>> I don't know cuz he's done promo posts
before and he's said this before when
we've talked we've talked to other
people about it and he's like promo
posts never do well for him. Like people
just kind of they're like, "Okay, cool.
I'll thanks. I'll I'll help you. I'll
I'll send you some dollars for your
socks, Hank, for your good cause and and
move on with their life." But those
videos did super well. They're very high
performing videos for him. And that's
where I think the artwork kicks in.
That's where all of the work of I want
this thing to catch someone's eye
immediately kicks in.
>> And not just anybody's eye, but
specifically his audience, right? Like
>> that feels like the big difference
between I wrote a book, I made some
socks, I it's like these are interesting
products that there's a ven diagram of
his audience and the product, but it's
it's minor. And so a lot of people
probably do it more to support the
creator than they do for the product.
But you made something that was like
trying to make that ven diagram just a
circle. Yeah. And that I have to imagine
combined with all the work on the the
artwork making again making it
specifically for that audience that had
to be a big part of of why it worked.
>> Yeah. The the combo I think a lot of
people uh cuz there are many other
creator apps but I don't think any of
them have done what Focus Friend did at
least in its first week in terms of like
how big it was in the press. But I could
be wrong. I could be totally wrong and
I'm fine being wrong.
>> I can't Yeah. I mean I can't think of
any. I'm sure there are and surely there
are like
>> if you go higher up in the celebrity I'm
sure there's like
>> major celebrities that have released
things that I don't necessarily know
about that have done super well.
>> Yeah, I think Arnold Schwarzenegger's
app does really well.
>> Yeah, that that is one. Yeah, my one of
the I don't remember his title now. He
was the director of marketing. I think
he's anyway person at our company love
like that's his favorite app ever is I
think it's called the pump and the
onboarding is like you're getting a
anybody should just go download the app
just to watch the onboarding cuz it's
like
>> it's like you're getting a motivational
>> Arnold Schwarzene so good so good and
actually it's funny you mentioned that
one cuz like we've actually worked
together a little bit recently because
we did a hackathon that was aimed at
this exact concept of
like
apps are an interesting way to monetize
an audience. Apps especially directed
that make sense for that audience and
that was one of the apps that sort of
spurred a lot of this thinking
internally at revenueat but then focus
friend is obviously an extreme example
of that. Yeah. So you released it
clearly it resonated. So but what was
that like? So he did a promotional post
and then what
>> I had my revenue cat notifications on
like a lot of indies probably did
and um and then suddenly I was like on a
walk with my partner and my daughter and
then like suddenly my phone just starts
like buzzing a lot and then I'm like
what's going I was like oh I'm getting a
there's a lot of people buying stuff.
What's going on? And then and then I see
that Hank had just posted about it and
he just had his arsenal of like
messaging. So I I have learned a good
amount about marketing with Tik Toks and
stuff, but this is the benefit of having
someone on my side that is just a genius
at what he does. He told me kind of the
angle he was going to take and I was
like, "All right, whatever." Oh, also
his brother John really loved the app.
So like I guess they just kind of
colluded on doing this like
>> kind of doubled up
>> campaign. Yeah, they doubled up on it
and they made two YouTube videos about
it and well it was the plan was just one
of them and then because after it hit
number one they did more. They kind of
colluded on like posting about it and
the messaging. I thought people would
care more about it being like a focus
timer, but people care way more about
they use it almost like an Opal
equivalent and they don't use it as a
just a timer. They use it as a screen
time control app. So that's where things
are getting a little bit or more
interesting for me now today on the
product side. But that was the angle
that they went for on the messaging too.
And that is that really resonated with
people and I was like, well, it's more
of a focus timer, but that's where my
engineering brain was kicking in. I was
like, well, technically, but they were
like, no, no, no, listen. And I just had
to trust them and they they're geniuses
at what they did.
>> That was the launch. It was just
>> them doing content on their channels.
Basically,
>> they have a combined channel together
and John did a one on his on their
YouTube channel that they jointly share
and then Hank did a series of Instagram
reels, Tik Tok, and then YouTube shorts.
>> Okay. It felt like the whole internet
was writing about it. I genuinely
thought when you said you switched
strategies that you were going to be
like, "All right, so we lined up these
press people. We got them on an early
version." Because it was like every like
every The Verge Ingadget, I don't know.
I'm I'm all saying them all the top of
my head because I feel like literally
everybody wrote about it, but everybody
who's writing about it was like as a
user and that all that all just came
from because it skyrocketed up and his
video made traction. It kind of worked
its way through all these circles.
>> Yeah. I guess people were talking about
it like it was the first time I'd ever
had people in my life, they were like,
"Oh my gosh, everyone's talking about
this Bean app right now."
>> Oh wow. Oh, and they you they didn't
>> in my own life. Yeah,
>> that's pretty crazy. Have you seen
anybody in real life using it like on a
on a subway or something?
>> People have said it in to me in person
like they they when I've said this is
what I made and then they're like oh
yeah my god yeah
>> that's so cool.
>> That was super duper cool. And like
there were people emailing me being like
oh my gosh I didn't know you made this
app or like I everyone's talking about
your app right now. Like I got a lot of
me those messages and and emails and
stuff. So very very very cool. But like
this is actually pretty funny. We hit
the top 10. And if anyone was on like
Twitter for a while, it was like the the
cool kids get to show off their top 10
that they hit the top 10. And I was
like, "Oh my gosh, I did it. I hit the
top 10 on the app store of overall in
the app store." And then Hank's like he
he texts me and he was like, "I want to
be number one." And chat GPT was number
one at this time. And then we did and I
was just like I didn't even know that
that was a possibility for us and it was
the coolest thing ever. It was awesome.
>> Did you have you framed that screenshot
on your wall?
>> I will I have I it is something I want
to Yeah. But I actually I have um I've
got
>> I've got this my app store.
>> Yeah. So that was actually my followup
is you you have some hardware. So, for
those listening on the podcast, do you
want to describe what you just grabbed
off your shelf?
>> We won an App Store award. That was also
one of the coolest experiences ever. And
then we were I I just can't reach it. I
have two more trophies right there.
>> Oh, I know one other. I don't know what
the third one is.
>> Um it So, we won the best app of 2025,
um Google Play. Then we also won the
best personal growth app. They sent me
two trophies, which I am very happy to I
know.
>> So, uh yeah, I can grab it or I can grab
one of them. Here we go.
>> Ooh.
>> Like, yeah.
>> All glass.
>> I am still waiting for my revenue cat
one, but I just haven't yet.
>> Yes. Yes. Uh have you got are we are we
sending one? I I don't remember.
>> It should be.
>> It is. Oh, yes. Right. Yeah. I can go
into long details about the the
manufacturing of those, but that's
that's been a thing. I'm really curious
about well any of those but in
particular the app store one because I
know Apple makes a pretty big
>> song and dance of it and like you get I
I think you had a like photographer cuz
your picture's on the app store and
there's a whole feature and profile
about you. What was that experience
like? How did you find out and then what
happened?
>> They reached out to me. So I did their
entrepreneur camp and every indie should
apply to it if it still exists. It's one
of those things if you're in the
developer advocate space, I think you
you probably know that programs get cut
and o and reopen all the time. So, but I
did that camp and I had been wanting to
get Boba Story featured for a super long
time and I think it just wasn't working
out and I learned a lot also about like
how to get an like a lot of mistakes
that I had made with Boba Story that I
had fixed with focus friend like what
really attracts an app store editor and
we can talk about that another time but
there's something that really that that
they're looking for and I think I'm
tried to re I've tried to do that with
um with focus friend as Well,
>> that's like my like dream talk to give
is cuz I feel like with my app, that's
pretty much the only marketing channel I
have is like trying to get featured on
the app store and it's worked pretty
well. But it's at least for me it seems
like it's mostly sounds like similar to
what you said you were trying to do once
the AI tools kicked in which is like
find those system integration features
that they want to promote. Mhm.
>> Give it live activities, give it screen
time access and all the things and like
make part of the narrative be, you know,
Apple technology has has really made
this possible. That's the kind of stuff
that seems like gets their attention for
sure.
>> I think like the the onboarding being
really easy to understand and a little
bit of design like those three things is
kind of where those meet. But they had
asked me to come out for a developer
showcase and I had just done a couple
things like before and I was like I was
running on fumes at this point like with
the Google like best app of 2025 like
there was so much that they were asking
of me and I just worked so hard and then
they reached out into about this
developer showcase and I was like I'm so
appreciative but oh my god I'm so tired
like I don't know if I want to go cuz
they weren't saying like they weren't
saying I was nominated for an app store
award or anything. They weren't saying
that. So, I was just like, I don't know,
y'all. Like, I just want to spend some
time with my with my family. I feel very
tired. And they were like, trust me, you
don't want to miss it. And they were
just trying to support me. And then they
like told me that I was nominated. I was
like, okay, that's so amazing. And then
they were really trying to convince me
to go cuz it was based in LA. I'm an
hour outside of LA. And they were just
really pushing for me to go. And then I
got my stuff together, got had
mother-in-law stay with with us for a
bit, and then I show up. They gave me a
hotel room and everything. And they're
like, "Okay, you're going to go take
your photo or you're going to do this
thing." When they brought us out to the
photographer, I was like just standing
there. And then they're like, "You won
the award." And they like took a picture
of me like accepting the award. Yeah.
Reacting. I was like, "Oh my god." And I
I like kept it together there, but like
then I had to go to another room and
like prepare and cuz I had to prepare
presentation. I had to get an interview.
And when I got to the room, I c I cried.
I was like, "What is going on?" Like
this whole year like this whole year
started off like awful and now like cuz
this was in December and it's ending on
like this high.
>> It's such a complete circle.
>> Yeah,
>> that's crazy.
>> Yeah. I had to go to therapy over it cuz
I was like it started to feel like oh my
god did my daughter have to go through
such a hard time just for this to
happen. Like my brain my like postpartum
brain kind of like made this connection
that like if my daughter didn't suffer
like I wouldn't have success and I was
like oh my god I want to throw this
success away so my kids don't have to.
Yeah. It was a very very very strange
thing. I've undone it but like yeah all
of that happening in one year both good
and also like kind of a like whoa what's
going on. It's a lot.
>> Mhm. A lot of emotions in one year.
>> Obviously released super successful,
lots of press, lots of downloads, lots
of hardware, you know, you have
trophies. Now in 2026, it's kind of it's
a going concern, right? It is the an app
that seems like it's doing well. Do you
feel like you succeeded in what you
described earlier as, you know, the big
pop and then you're trying not to just
fall all the way down? Have you has it
leveled off in a state where you're like
this is a sustainable business?
>> I think so. I think so. I would like it
to get higher because like I'd mentioned
before, the goalpost has moved. I've
officially replaced the tech salary. So,
I I've officially replaced the tech
salary. So, that's good. I approved my
initial thesis, but I'm like, is this
something another person could
replicate? I'm not sure. Yeah. Um, yeah.
I'm not sure about this exact
trajectory, but um, I feel like I
learned enough along the way to help
someone get to I was like, someone could
get to to 200K, I think, like someone
without a tech background pretty
systematically, I think. So, Opal and
all the other screen time apps like Be
Present, those have higher revenues per
month than other focus timers. So, I
would love to get to those levels.
That's something that would be really
interesting for me. So Hank Green is
known as someone who's given away the
majority of his wealth. Like if I think
you know that, but I don't think the
audience knows that.
>> He's known as someone who has like
raised
>> tens and ten like maybe over hundreds of
millions of dollars and he's him and his
brother have given it all away. And
because of that and because of having
that reputation, we made a lot of
decision like product decisions that I'm
like we probably could have made three
to even 10 times what we have made if we
were a lot more like we had a hard payw
wall for example or if we were more
pestering or had were very strategic on
like when you show the when you show the
subscription when you what deciding what
you put behind it using sales and things
like that to try and get people to
convert. And because of that, now my
work, I'm trying to do less engineering.
So, I hired another engineer who's a way
better Unity engineer than I am. I have
someone like a contractor that can help
with like native stuff on iOS and
hopefully AI can take the wheel for
Android native. But that's kind of where
I'm at right now. We're in that weird
space between game and app where there's
like a content treadmill within with a
game and it's not like an app where it's
a habit but there has to be content for
them to keep going.
>> You have to keep feeding the machine.
>> Yeah. So that's something that's where a
lot of my where my work lies now is
trying to really it's almost like game
design too where it's like I have to
figure out where how this loop fits
together and what features. There's tons
of features still that people are that
people want and that so we have a lot of
growth in terms of the product and
making their product even better. I'm
doing the side on marketing. So Hank did
he did like that initial push but like
part of his job is just to stay famous
and so he has he has to do like his his
own stuff and he has like other other
ventures that he's working on. So now
it's on me to figure out like how to
grow the app and that's kind of where
I'm in like a CEO CTO role right now.
It's tough, but it's excit It's just a
new set of skills for sure. Ah,
>> that's so cool. I guess before we kind
of get to the end here, based on kind of
what we talked about earlier, if there's
people listening that hear this and
they're like, "Yes, this working with an
influencer to help them monetize their
audience sounds like a cool thing."
Obviously, your story specifically is
unique in the connections that you had,
but everybody has different connections,
but like what advice would you have to
somebody? I guess a would you recommend
people do this? And then B, what would
you re is there any advice you'd have
for people that are trying to go that
route for things that they should
specifically think about or look out for
or ways to structure themselves uh to
set up for success if they're going to
if they're going to try and build an app
in this kind of way.
>> You kind of have two options if you
don't have a lot of money to do paid
acquisition and stuff cuz like it it's
so it's getting very expensive to do
paid acquisition. So doing organic and
you have two options if you want to do
organic. I think in this day and age if
you're an indie and you can either
become an influencer for your app and
there's an inflection point. It is hard
to both be an influ a good influencer
and be a good developer. It's a lot of
work. I did it. It's possible but it's a
lot of work. So you can either do that.
you can add someone on your team that
becomes the influencer like that it does
not have an audience yet and build an
audience at the same time as building
your app or three you can partner with
an influencer that you trust. So I like
to do this exercise. This is just
something that's really fun for me. I
will just take a random influencer and
then come up with an idea for them
>> for for like what I think would do well
with their audience. So, this is just a
personal opinion on my end because I've
had to be a product manager and I've
done a lot of work on on this. I don't
think that influencers really know what
a good idea is for them to do for their
audience. They always, for some reason,
they always want a social media or they
want like a feed of information. And I'm
just like, no. I I just don't think that
those are good ideas for apps
personally.
>> Their expertise is somewhere else by
sort of definition, right? Unless
they're like a tech influencer. Yeah.
And even so, I'm just like, no one's
going to download an app to get very
niche information. I just don't think
so.
>> Well, and what's popular and what's
monetizable are also often different
things.
>> I love utility apps. So, sometimes,
like, and they're not too hard to build.
Sometimes I like to take a niche of apps
that seem easy to build and then try to
pair them with influencers I think they
would do well with or I just choose a
random influencer and I'm like let me
just design what this app could be in my
head and what I think would do well for
their audience. So those are kind of
like two ways in terms of creating a
product for an influencer and then to
actually work with one. You'd be
surprised. So influencers or YouTubers,
creators, they don't have a lot of
options for monetizing and they are way
worse at monetizing than you think that
they are. Even ones that do like really
big like merch things, like that's not
sustainable for them long term. They get
paid from brand deals, they don't have a
lot of passive income. The only passive
income they have is from affiliate
links. So like if it's oh buy this
Amazon stuff in my bio or if they have
like a digital course or digital
products and stuff like that. So I just
like to think of apps as being a
potential digital product.
>> And then is the best approach for how to
like would you do you think doing a
split like ownership split is kind of
the thing that makes the most sense?
>> Yes. Well I have Hank and I have a lot
of trust. So currently we have a split
on the revenues but not on the
ownership. But that's something because
if we ever want to do like a sale or
something like that because it's done
well. He said that he's fine with
changing equity split to just being
between us. But I think it makes the
influencer feel a lot more um in a
position of ownership if they own the IP
for example. So, it's like they own the
IP and this is where it's hard and I
just have to say what I did and
hopefully this works out and everyone
has to just figure out what works well
for them because Hank upfronted the
money like a lot of the money from the
be or at least like we had an agreement
but I chose to not get paid for the
work. That's something I chose. I chose
that my money is going to come from the
other end after launch and from the
revenue cuz if you don't do that then
it's going to be like they get 80% you
get 20% for example in terms of revenue
on the other side if they upfront a lot
of money to pay you in the beginning
>> right it's a kind of risk anal risk
analysis I guess there
>> yeah so I chose to not get paid and to
just support myself through Boba story
while making focus friend and all of the
money went to like contractors and just,
you know, all of the artwork and stuff
like that. So, that's up to up to
another person of what's comfortable to
them. A lot of people told me that I was
dumb for doing that. They said that I
should be getting paid like 200k, for
example, for the work of actually making
the app. And I'm like, well, they were
if he was going to a dev studio to make
his idea for an app, that makes sense.
But this is just a collaboration. And a
lot of influencers or creators,
whatever, they don't have 200k to just
give you. There are some that do and
there's like another AI coaching app
made by some New York Times person. I
forgot I forgot his name, but yeah, I'm
not sure. But he I know they're at like
2 million ARR whatever, but he funneled
a million dollars of his own money into
making the app. And most most people
aren't going to be able to do that.
>> I would guess that there's a big benefit
to there being
equity and upside for both parties,
right? like once once it gets going,
>> it's like it's easier to work on it when
you get to like after it's launched,
it's a lot easier to keep working on it
and care about it
>> when you have equity in there. And it's
a lot easier to continue promoting it if
if you on the creator side have equity
in it. And so that kind of shared upside
feels like it just it's it makes a lot
of sense in in this kind of setup.
>> And they are also very distracted, very
distractable and distracted. So don't
expect to have someone who's like really
like a co- like it's like that's really
really in it and they might be for a few
months but then they're going to be like
okay I've got other stuff to do because
the development cycle just takes a long
time. So choosing the right one matters
a lot.
>> That is amazing. I think we've kind of
reached this the current point in time.
I'm excited to see everything you do
from here. But uh before we end, I got
to ask you the the question that I ask
everybody to end the show, which is
what's a people or person out there that
have influenced you in your work that
you'd recommend others check out?
>> There's a woman named Laura Rotor. She's
the founder of a company called
Paperbell right now. She has sold two
SAS companies and she talks a lot on her
platforms about like balancing having
like a very balanced motherhood and like
she was able to I think get to like 15
million in net worth just from her SAS
companies that she's sold. She has like
two kids and she just like spends a lot
of time with her family. She's found
that delicate balance of someone who
spends a lot of time being present and
also like very very very good
businesswoman. So, that's someone that
inspires me right now.
>> Oh, man. Okay, that's awesome. Yeah,
I'll have to I'll have to check her out.
Um, cool. All right. Well, thank you so
much for doing this. This was super fun.
And I don't know, it's one of those
stories that I feel like I knew the
story and then as we're talking it's
like I didn't know almost any of the
real story. And so, this was this was uh
super good. Um, where can people uh
listening find you and your work? I'm
not really on a lot of social media
right now other than maybe LinkedIn. So,
just Bria Sullivan on LinkedIn.
>> Well, thank you all for uh listening.
So, Launched is part of the RevenueCat
podcast family. If you'd like to learn
more about the growth side of mobile app
businesses, you should check out SubC by
my friend uh David Barnard and check
out, of course, revenuecat.com to learn
about the easiest way to grow and
monetize your mobile app business. Uh,
for launched, you can find Launched at
launchedfm.com.
And we're pretty much all over the
internet. Uh, usually the handle is
launched, including our YouTube channel,
which, uh, is where you could go. And if
you're watching, you saw the amazing
trophy collection that Bria has been
collecting. So, definitely check that
out if you are into the the visual side
of video podcasts. Uh, and yeah, that's
all I got. So, I will see you all in two
weeks. Bye.
There you go.